Welcome back to a push in under 3
minutes. No time for intros. Let's get
into it. So, it's fair to say that all
the immigration coming into the United
States during this guilded age was not
that wellreceived by American society.
America has mostly always stood on the
principle of the acceptance of any sort
of immigration. At least that's what
they say on the surface. Behind the
scenes, there was a lot of debates and
quite a bit of governmental action as
well. So, let's give a few examples.
First of all, do you remember all those
Chinese immigrants that risked their
lives to do dangerous work building the
transcontinental railroad? Well, here's
a fun story. There was so much
anti-Asian racism that by 1882, America
passed the Chinese Exclusion Act that
put a 10-year ban on any new Chinese
labor immigration. But you also have
good things, too. Like, for example, in
the Supreme Court case US versus Wong
Kim Arc, it established and solidified
birthright citizenship, meaning anyone
born in the US is a US citizen. A good
book to reference here might be Rose
Cohan's Out of the Shadow. This book
follows the tale of Rose who immigrated
into the US as a Jewish immigrant and
shows her struggles to maintain her
culture as she worked through countless
sweat shops. Another thing to note here
is the work of women, or more
specifically, one woman named Jane
Adams. She's known for doing quite a lot
of stuff, but for this time period, what
you should know is that she co-founded
the famous Whole House where she would
aid the poor along with immigrants. Also
during this time you have people all
over the place wanting to justify their
class, race or just status in society.
And this is where an ideology takes hold
known as social Darwinism. Essentially
what this means is applying the quote
survival of the fittest ideal to
society. Or for a better definition,
social Darwinism argues that the strong
naturally dominate the weak and that
social inequality, racism, and
imperialism are justified as natural
outcomes of competition. Now, of course,
I'm not even going to get into how this
is completely wrong and how it
completely misapplies Charles Darwin's
original thinking. Rather, I just want
you to know that this very controversial
ideology was used in this time period to
justify the success of those on top of
the social ladder. And that's it for
this one. On the screen now are AP style
questions for this topic. Pause now.
I'll put the answers on the screen now.
I will see you in the next one.